<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jake VanCampen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jake VanCampen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to make goslides</title>
      <link>/post/how-to-goslides/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/how-to-goslides/</guid>
      <description>Creating Slides in Golang I am about to give a journal club presentation on a recent epigenetics paper. I have also been learning golang. Many learning materials, and golang presentations I run into are very clean html presentations with absolutely no bells and whistles, that appear to run in the browser.
I soon found out these presentations are generated from the &amp;lsquo;present&amp;rsquo; package, which is a builtin golang tool at golang.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning golang for bioinformatics</title>
      <link>/post/learning-golang-for-bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/learning-golang-for-bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description>What is Go? Go, or &amp;ldquo;golang&amp;rdquo; is a compiled language that was developped at Google in 2009. Golang is an open source language designed for simplicity, and portability within modern computational infrastructures. Golang is statically typed. In practice this means defining the types of variables, and explicitly keeping track of how those types are passed into and out of functions.
Hello World in go looks like this:
package main import &amp;#34;fmt&amp;#34; func main() { fmt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conda and containers</title>
      <link>/post/conda-and-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conda-and-containers/</guid>
      <description>Conda and Containers Planemo documentation
Galaxy dependencies are resolved by dependency resolvers (conda). Conda recipes build packages that are published to chanels.
For Galacy, Conda manages multiple versions maybe better than brew, apt. YAML and shell recipes. Annotated source packages provides better reproducibility.
Why not just use docker?
 Singularity has been a solution for those that don&amp;rsquo;t want to just run docker.   Best Practice Channels
 iuc, bioconda, conda-forge, defaults   To use conda outside Planemo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GATK 4.0</title>
      <link>/post/new-gatk-4-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-gatk-4-0/</guid>
      <description>What&amp;rsquo;s new in GATK 4.0  Catered to illumina short read sequencing Pre-processing, variant analysis. Goal is to identify variation between genomes  GATK 4.0 was rewritten from scratch for dramatic performance improvements and new functional capabilities such as:
 structural variant detection advanced machine learning techniques best-practice workflows All Picard tools bundled in GATK executable   Speed optimizations  Intel genomics kernal library (GKL) increased spead and hardware optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to galaxy admin</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-galaxy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-galaxy/</guid>
      <description>Into to Galaxy Admin &amp;ndash; Morning Using Ansible to setup a Galaxy Ansible is an automated computer management system that can be used to install and configure software infastructure. Ansible scripts are called playbooks, written as yaml files, can be structured in folder hierarchy with mnay available modules.
Why: - avoid forgetting what you did to install and configure some software - codify knowledge about system - &amp;ldquo;make infastructure programmable&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a jupyter notebook server</title>
      <link>/post/setup-a-jupyter-notebook-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/setup-a-jupyter-notebook-server/</guid>
      <description>Setup a jupyter notebook server This document is a quick how to on running Jupyter notebook/lab a remote server.
Setup Make sure you have an up to date install of anaconda or miniconda. If you need to, install miniconda3 in your home directory:
cd ~ wget https://repo.continuum.io/miniconda/Miniconda3-4.5.4-Linux-x86_64.sh bash Miniconda3-latest-Linux-x86_64.sh Follow the commands to install using defaults, then restart your terminal session. When you update or install programs using this version of conda, their executable is stored in: /home//miniconda3/bin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align and count RNA-seq reads with STAR</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-12-align-and-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-12-align-and-count/</guid>
      <description>DNA makes RNA makes Protein, as goes the central dogma of molecular biology. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) allows researchers to quantify which genes of the DNA are being expressed at any given time, in a given sample of DNA. This tool is very powerful because it allows us to ask questions about the difference in gene expression between different individuals, or between time points in the same individual.
RNA-seq produces a text file with millions of sequences we call &amp;lsquo;reads&amp;rsquo; that represent the genes they came from in the genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply Times</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-09-reply-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-09-reply-times/</guid>
      <description>I wrote up an analysis of imessage data in jupyter notebook and found out that I may actually reply faster to my girlfriend over text during the daytime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMRT Sequencing for smart genomics</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-03-smrt-sequencing-for-smart-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-03-smrt-sequencing-for-smart-genomics/</guid>
      <description>The University of Oregon Genomics and Cell Characterization Core Facility (GCCCF) hosted a seminar this past Friday, November 3rd in celebration of the new Pacific Biosciences sequencer, the Sequel, that is now accepting submissions for long-read sequencing.
Advances in SMRT sequencing The seminar kicked off with Steve Turner, Chief Technology Officer at PacBio. Turner&amp;rsquo;s excitement was contagious as he described the advantages of long-read sequencing technologies on the new Sequel system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Development Environment</title>
      <link>/post/2017-10-26-my-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-10-26-my-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>When I began working on the computer full time earlier this year, I was still using the GUIs of my computer and had little intuition for how to organize my work in a coding Environment. Now I use exclusively the command line to navigate my MacBook Pro; collaborate and track my work using Github; and I write most assignments, and now blog posts in markdown.
The largest behavioral change for me was working primarily in text editors, Github, and the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/bio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/bio/</guid>
      <description>I work as a bioinformatics researcher in the Genomics core at the Stowers Institute for Medical Research. I am passionate about applying computational tools to biological questions. I am interested in providing reproducible solutions to biological data analysis, for example: I like to use well-maintained workflow management systems such as Snakemake, and git for version control.
I am currently working on genomic investigation of three populations of Astyanax mexicanus with strikingly different morphologies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>/cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/cv/</guid>
      <description>Curriculum Vitae  Education MS Bioinformatics and Genomics | University of Oregon | Expected Dec. 2018
BS Biochemistry, ACS Certified | University of Portland | May 2017
 Skills Languages: Python R bash git Stan
 Work Experience Graduate Researcher (Genomics) - Stowers Institute for Medical Research - (04/2018-current)
 Perform Bioinformatic analyses in the Computational Biology/Genomics department. Utilize workflow management (snakemake) and version control (git) for maximal reproducibility, and reusability of computational pipelines.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>