<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jake VanCampen</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jake VanCampen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conda and containers</title>
      <link>/post/conda-and-containers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/conda-and-containers/</guid>
      <description>Conda and Containers Planemo documentation
Galaxy dependencies are resolved by dependency resolvers (conda). Conda recipes build packages that are published to chanels.
Conda Features for galaxy:
Conda manages multiple versions maybe better than brew, apt.
YAML and shell recipes. Annotated source packages provides better reproducibility.
Why not just use docker?
 Singularity has been a solution for those that don’t want to just run docker.  Best Practice Channels
 iuc, bioconda, conda-forge, defaults  To use conda outside Planemo:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New GATK 4.0</title>
      <link>/post/new-gatk-4-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/new-gatk-4-0/</guid>
      <description>What’s new in GATK 4.0  Catered to illumina short read sequencing Pre-processing, variant analysis. Goal is to identify variation between genomes  GATK 4.0 was rewritten from scratch for dramatic performance improvements and new functional capabilities such as:
 structural variant detection advanced machine learning techniques best-practice workflows All Picard tools bundled in GATK executable  Speed optimizations  Intel genomics kernal library (GKL) increased spead and hardware optimizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>commmon workflow language</title>
      <link>/post/commmon-workflow-language/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/commmon-workflow-language/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro to galaxy1</title>
      <link>/post/intro-to-galaxy1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/intro-to-galaxy1/</guid>
      <description>Into to Galaxy Admin Using Ansible to setup a Galaxy What is ansible:
 Automation of tool config and computer management. multi-node software dev, ad-hoc task execution, configurmation managemnet.  Why: - avoid forgetting what you did to install and configure some software - codify knowledge about system - “make infastructure programmable”
Ansible features: - easy to learn (YAML playbooks, jinja2 templates, INI inventory ) - sequential execution
Ansible scripts are called playbooks, written as yaml files, can be structured in folder hierarchy with mnay available modules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>test_rmd</title>
      <link>/post/test-rmd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/test-rmd/</guid>
      <description>This is a test generated Rmd file. This will test how the .Rmd is rendered into html by examining the creation of plots and code chunks.
# This is a code chunk &amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; print(&amp;quot;Hello, World!&amp;quot;) Let’s test the R code chunk
print(&amp;quot;This is an R code chunk&amp;quot;) ## [1] &amp;quot;This is an R code chunk&amp;quot; ## a fast way to generate *sorted* U[0,1] random numbers: rsunif &amp;lt;- function(n) { n1 &amp;lt;- n+1 cE &amp;lt;- cumsum(rexp(n1)); cE[seq_len(n)]/cE[n1] } plot(rsunif(1000), ylim=0:1, pch=&amp;quot;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Align and count RNA-seq reads with STAR</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-12-align-and-count/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-12-align-and-count/</guid>
      <description>DNA makes RNA makes Protein, as goes the central dogma of molecular biology. RNA sequencing (RNA-seq) allows researchers to quantify which genes of the DNA are being expressed at any given time, in a given sample of DNA. This tool is very powerful because it allows us to ask questions about the difference in gene expression between different individuals, or between time points in the same individual.
RNA-seq produces a text file with millions of sequences we call &amp;lsquo;reads&amp;rsquo; that represent the genes they came from in the genome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reply Times</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-09-reply-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-09-reply-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote up an analysis of imessage data in jupyter notebook and found out that I may actually reply faster to my girlfriend over text during the daytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;{{ site.url }}/assets/imgs/replytimes_day.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;{:class=&amp;ldquo;img-responsive&amp;rdquo;}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMRT Sequencing for smart genomics</title>
      <link>/post/2017-11-03-smrt-sequencing-for-smart-genomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-11-03-smrt-sequencing-for-smart-genomics/</guid>
      <description>The University of Oregon Genomics and Cell Characterization Core Facility (GCCCF) hosted a seminar this past Friday, November 3rd in celebration of the new Pacific Biosciences sequencer, the Sequel, that is now accepting submissions for long-read sequencing.
Advances in SMRT sequencing The seminar kicked off with Steve Turner, Chief Technology Officer at PacBio. Turner&amp;rsquo;s excitement was contagious as he described the advantages of long-read sequencing technologies on the new Sequel system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Development Environment</title>
      <link>/post/2017-10-26-my-development-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2017-10-26-my-development-environment/</guid>
      <description>When I began working on the computer full time earlier this year, I was still using the GUIs of my computer and had little intuition for how to organize my work in a coding Environment. Now I use exclusively the command line to navigate my MacBook Pro; collaborate and track my work using Github; and I write most assignments, and now blog posts in markdown.
The largest behavioral change for me was working primarily in text editors, Github, and the command line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I work as a bioinformatics researcher in the genomics core at the Stowers Institute for Medical Research. I am passionate about applying computational tools to biological questions. I am interested in providing reproducible solutions to biological data analysis, for example: I like to use well-maintained workflow management systems such as Snakemake, and git for version control.
I am currently working on genomic investigation of three populations of Astyanax mexicanus with strikingly different morphologies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>